Jonathan Sloan

- **(**419) 388-9364
- isloan117@gmail.com
- in LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-sloan-52a808146)
- GitHub (https://github.com/jsloan117)

ABOUT

A Certified Linux System Administrator with experience in the daily operations, support and maintenance for Linux operating systems, and servers. Managed web services and providing support for Linux system-related issues and requests for all clients.

EXPERIENCE

Compliance Specialist, A2 Hosting (https://www.a2hosting.com/)

June 2015 — July 2017 ② 2 years

A2 Hosting a web hosting company based out of Ann Arbor Michigan. They offer everything from a basic website to high-performance dedicated servers.

- Worked remotely from home.
- Supported Customers via Phone, Live Chat, and Support Tickets.
- Monitored Exim mail queues and logs for spam and other malicious activity using nagios.
- Monitored our IP address for blacklisting issues and handled them based on our policies.
- Helped to document procedures and policies, regarding compromised accounts and blacklisting issues.
- Reviewed abusive accounts and proceeded accordingly per our procedures and or policies.
- Worked with 3rd party abuse companies to take down malicious sites.
- Created bash scripts to help automate and obtain information from logs.

Linux Support Analyst, A2 Hosting (https://www.a2hosting.com/)

December 2013 — June 2015 ② a year

A2 Hosting a web hosting company based out of Ann Arbor Michigan. They offer everything from a basic website to high-performance dedicated servers.

- Worked remotely from home.
- Supported Customers via Phone, Live Chat, and Support Tickets.
- Migrated client cPanel accounts from other hosts to our servers as well as internally.
- Assisted customers with pre-sales and sales questions.
- Provided server-side support for hosting services.
- Review abusive accounts and proceed accordingly.
- Work with 3rd party abuse companies to take down malicious sites.

EDUCATION

Computer Information Systems concentrated in Cyber Defense, Bachelor

2011 — Present **②** 6 years

Baker College

Cisco Systems and general IT 2007 — 2009 **②** 2 years

Four County Career Center



Linux Systems Administration

CentOS Ubuntu Scripting Management Monitoring Security

Troubleshooting Services

DNS HTTP POP3/IMAP SMTP FTP MySQL

General IT

Networking Technical Support Computer Repair Troubleshooting Hardware & Software Customer Service

Documentation | Software Installation

Automation & Development

Bash | Git

P AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

Linux+, CompTIA

Certified on: Oct 27, 2017

LPIC-1, LPI

Certified on: Oct 27, 2017

Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition, National CCDC

Awarded in: 2013

Regional contestant

PC Servicing & Troubleshooting, Business Professional of America

Awarded in: 2009
State contestant

PC Servicing & Troubleshooting, Business Professional of America

Awarded in: 2008
State contestant



DevOps & Development

Chef||Automation||Cl_pipeline||Cookbooks||Inspec||Ruby

Linux Administration

Bash Scripting Installing & troubleshooting software



English, Native speaker



— Available upon request.